网络是一个非常深的
Networking is a very deep,
非常深藏的知识汇集了我的表面层
very deep pool of knowledge that I
have just the surface layer of this.
我要向大家介绍 Docker 的网络，但是
So I'm going to introduce you to
what networking in Docker is, but
承认我们只是在挠它的表面
recognize that we're just
scratching the surface here.
有人说他们整个工作只是在网络里工作
There are people that their entire job
is just working on networking stuff, so
我不会假装我有那么多的知识
I'm not gonna pretend that I have
that kind of knowledge, here.
那么让我们回到我们的 TERMINAL。
So let's come back to our TERMINAL.
如果你说码头网络你应该看到类似的东西
If you say docker network ls,
you should see something akin to this,
我觉得这个是 Docker 节点 - 一个是以前的 Kubernetes 项目，
I think this is docker-node-one is I
have from a previous Kubernetes project,
但你可能看到桥，主机和空
but you probably see bridge,
host, and null,
那就是你现在很可能看到的 3 个
those are the three you very
likely are seeing right now.
我甚至可以说 Docker 网络是那个
I could probably even just say
docker network rm that one.
好了现在你可以看到我只有 3 个了
Okay, so
now you can see I just have three, and
我想你会看到类似的东西对吧
I imagine you see something akin to that,
right?
因此 Docker 允许您进行连接，连接到缺省网桥网络，
So docker allows you to one,
connect to the default bridge network,
这叫做 " 桥梁" 是我们要合作的
which is called bridge, right and that's
the one that we're gonna be working with,
是网桥网络。
is bridge networks.
这样你就可以把两个容器连接起来，对吧 ?
And then this allows you to connect
two containers to each other, right?
所以如果我有这个特殊的微型服务需要和这个特定的
So if I have this particular microservice
needs to talk to this particular
微服务，我可以创建一个 Docker 网络，允许两个容器
microservice, I can create a docker
network that allows the two containers to
彼此交谈对吧
talk to each other, right?
这里是个想法一般都不推荐你
It's kind of the idea here and
generally don't recommend that you
使用缺省网桥网络，他们要求您创建自己的网桥。
use The default bridge network
they ask you to create your own.
所以我们要做的就是 Docker 网络
So that's what we're gonna do
we're gonna say Docker network,
创建 -- driver=bridge，然后可以调用任何您想要的，
create -- driver=bridge, and
then you can call whatever you want,
但我们会打电话给我们的应用网络我很有创意
but we're gonna call ours
app net cuz I'm creative.
所以现在如果我们说 Docker 网络 LS
So now if we say Docker network LS,
你可以看到我们有一个应用网桥，对吧 ?
you can see here we have
an app net bridge, right?
所以现在我们就像一个任意的网络，可以把各种容器连接起来，
So now we have like an arbitrary network
that we can connect various containers to,
然后连接到该或网络的任何容器可以相互交谈。
and then any containers that are connected
to that or network can talk to each other.
所以让我们把它连接起来，让我们把一个正在运行的微型或
So let's connect something to it,
let's connect a running micro or
用于此网络的 MongoDB 服务器。
a MongoDB server to this network.
所以 MongoDB对于那些不知道的人是一个 NoSQL 数据库
So MongoDB, for those of you that
don't know is a NoSQL database,
这是我个人最喜欢的一个，对很多节点开发者都很熟悉，
it's one of my personal favorites,
it's familiar to a lot of node developers,
但允许您将 JSON 与数据库交谈，并且它的非结构化性非常大。
but allows you to speak JSON to a database
and it's unstructured which is great.
所以我要说 docker run-d --network=app-net，
So I'm gonna say docker
run-d --network=app-net,
然后我得揭穿它的港口
then I have to expose
the port that it's on,
就是 2701727017
which is 27017.27017,
这是 MongoDB 的默认值，我们会给它一个数据库的名称。
that's the default MongoDB one,
we're gonna give it a name of db.
你可以更有创意我只是懒惰的 RM
You can be more creative than that, I'm
just lazy -- RM to remove it at the end,
我们要做傻子 3我有一个新版本的蒙古人
and we're gonna do Mongo:3,
there's a newer version of Mongo but
每个人都坚持三个因为我有所有司机
everyone stick to three because I
have all the drivers working for
蒙哥 3 号好吗
Mongo three as well, Okay?
所以你应该把它从背景上开始
So you should run that and
it'll start up on the background, so
现在如果我说博士我应该知道我有个蒙戈服务器
now if I say docker ps I should see that I
have a Mongo server that's probably still
开始吧好吗
starting up, Okay?
我现在要做的是启动第二个蒙戈容器
So, what I'm gonna do now is I'm
gonna start a second Mongo container
因为 Mongos 容器中都包含了 Mongod ，而 Mongod 实际上是服务器
because the Mongos container contains
both Mongod which is actually the server
它在后台运行，它还包含 Mongo 客户机。
that runs in the background,
it also contains the Mongo client.
所以我要用一个容器跟另一个容器说话，这有道理吗 ?
So I'm gonna use one container to talk to
the other container, does that make sense?
所以我们来试试，我说 docker run - it --network=app-net --rm，
So let's try it, I'm gonna say docker
run -it --network=app-net --rm,
我们要去买蒙哥 3 号的集装箱
and we're gonna get the Mongo 3 container,
and
我们要说的是主数据库我必须再次输入蒙古人
we're gonna say -- host db,
I have to type Mongo again.
所以在你输入蒙古人 3 之后，我们希望它与 Mongo 客户端一起运行，对吧 ?
So after you type Mongo three, we want
it to run with the Mongo client, right?
这是我们给它的指令
This is the command we're giving it,
好了 docker run- it network=app net -rm， mongo 3，
Okay, so docker run- it
network=app net --rm, mongo 3,
mongo ，实际上是说运行 mongo 客户机，对吧 ?
mongo which is actually say
run the mongo client, right?
可以连接到它并对其运行查询的数据库客户机，对吗 ?
The database client where you can connect
to it and run queries against it, right?
然后 --主持人数据库，对吧 ?
And then --host db, right?
很酷的是我把这个数据库叫做 " 数据库 "
So what's cool about this is I called
this db right up here in the names,
将把数据库的 URL 改为 localhost的 URL 而不是像 localhost一样
that's going to make the URL of db
right instead of like localhost,
数据库会连接到网络上的另一个叫 db 的吧
it's gonna be db connects to the other
one on the network called db, right?
有道理吗
That make sense?
所以如果我这样做，就应该把我放到 MongoDB 里，对吧 ?
So if I run this, it should drop me
into MongoDB which is did, right?
所以如果我说的是 DB 的，我可以看出来，
So if I say show DB's,
I can see that this that and
我可以说用测试机好吗
I can say use tester, okay?
然后我可以说 db.someCollection.insertOne({
So then I can say
db.someCollection.insertOne({
x:1}) 我自己给我留下了深刻的印象，我想起了如何做到这一点。
x:1}) wow I'm impressed with myself
that I remembered how to do that.
好了既然我说的是收藏
Okay so
now if I say like show collections,
我在这里已经创建了一个集合，意思是，这是一个真实的数据库，
I've created a sum collection here anyway,
point being, this is a real database,
存储在另一个 MangoDB 的容器里
it's storing stuff somewhere which
is in another MangoDB container.
现在，我可以使用卷将 MongoDB 实例输出到卷，并且
Now, I could use volumes to have this
MongoDB instance right out to a volume and
那么这个在运行之间也会是持续的，对吧 ?
then this would be persistent
between runs as well, right?
现在不这样做，因为这不是重点，
Not doing that right now,
because that's not the point of this but,
这里的重点是我在这里有个蒙哥的集装箱
the point here is that I have
this Mongo container over here,
和那个蒙哥的集装箱谈话
talking to this Mongo
container over there.
只是为了证明我的意思如果我说的是在另一个外壳上的码头
And just to kind of prove my point,
if I say docker ps in a different shell,
你可以看到我这里有一个季风 3 ，这个是在 2707 上运行的，
you can see here I have one mongo 3 here,
and this is running on 2707, or
这个比较，这个叫 db，对吧 ?
this one is rather, and
this one's called db, right?
这实际上是运行中的数据库
That's actually the running database and
如果我说 docker 顶级数据库就能看到它在运行 Mongod 对吧
you can see here if I say docker top db,
it's running Mongod, right?
>> Mongod。
&gt;&gt; Mongod.
> > 那是什么 ?
&gt;&gt; What's that?
>> Mongod。
&gt;&gt; Mongod.
> > Mongod 之类的
&gt;&gt; Mongod, something like that yeah.
>> 网络相互连接，因为它们在同一网络上吗 ?
&gt;&gt; And network into each other
because they're on the same network?
他们被允许了对吧
&gt;&gt; Yeah, they're allowed to, right?
它们都连接到应用网络上
Cuz they're both connected to App net,
and so
现在这个数据库里面特别提到这个数据库，
now DB inside of this one refers
to this database particularly,
所以如果你说 ping http://db
so if you say ping http://db,
它会在那边撞向另一个容器有道理吗
it'll hit the other container over there,
does that make sense?
>> 因此，卷将在数据库数据库中。
&gt;&gt; So
the volumes would In the db database.
>> 将卷连接到该卷，并将其连接到数据库
&gt;&gt; You connect the volumes
to this one yeah, to db, and
然后您可以配置 mongo ( 其中存储数据 ) ，
then you can configure mongo
where it stores its data,
您只需将其配置为将数据存储在卷上。
you would just configure it to
store the data on the volume.
然后再看它起回的时候我要告诉你怎么做
And then to read it when it starts back
up, I'm showing you how to do this by
再来一次因为我要给你展示一下如何不要用手来做，对吧 ?
hand, again, because I'm gonna show you
later how to not do this by hand, right?
通常，您不会直接与 Docker 网络进行消息传递，
Typically you're not going to be
messing with Docker networks directly,
你会有一些工具为你设定网络
you're gonna have tools that
are setting those networks for you, but
我想告诉你们这里真的没有什么神秘的，你可以用手来做。
I wanna show you there's really no
mystery here, you can do it by hand.
所以我要离开数据库了如果我说停手你可以看到 db 的
So I'm gonna leave db running, if I say
docker ps, you can see the db is still
正在运行，现在我们将编写一个节点应用程序，用于与 Mongo 交谈。
running, now we're going to write a node
application that speaks to the Mongo.